## AMANDA M. WILLIAMS

757.828.5756 ■ AMANDAWILLIAMS1915@GMAIL.COM ■ LINKEDIN.COM/IN/AMANDAMWILLIAMS1/

### **DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR**

Professional Analytics Engineer, Software Developer and Database Administrator with over five years of experience in Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, and .Net technologies. Skilled in relational and non-relational database management, system testing, analysis and optimization to ensure secure infrastructure. DoD secret security clearance and one year of GS-07 level experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS			
Programming Languages, Frameworks/Libraries	Tools & Technologies	Methodologies	Software/IDEs
SQL (MySQL, Oracle PL/SQL), HTML, .Net, Java, JavaScript/JSON, Python, Spring Boot, React.js, Node.js, Natural	SAP ERP, C4C Cloud, IBM Storage Protection backup, IBM Cognos Analytics, ADABAS, Azure DevOps Server/TFS, Git (Terminal, Bash, PowerShell), RESTful APIs.	Agile, Scrum, Test-driven Development, Object- oriented Programming, Microservices, SoftwareAG	Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint), IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio, NaturalONE

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Kaeser Compressors, Inc. – New Castle, DE IT Specialist, Inside Sales (Full time, 40 hours/week)

March 2024 - Current

- Acted as the technical point of contact for technical and non-technical stakeholders, leveraging expertise in SAP ERP and C4C cloud applications.
- Maintained internal databases to manage customer accounts and incoming sales orders.
- Thoroughly reviewed sales orders to identify and rectify inaccuracies, ensuring precision and adherence to technical specifications.
- Leveraged artificial intelligence prompting to develop and execute an email campaign targeting underperforming products, leading to a 40% increase in product sales within a two-month period.

# Naval Facilities Engineering Command (NAVFAC) – Norfolk, VA December 2022 – January 2024 IT Specialist - Sys Analysis (Full time, 40 hours/week, GS-2210-09, DoD Clearance: Secret)

- Developed and maintained PL/SQL-based software applications aligned with functional and technical requirements, ensuring timely deployment of robust solutions.
- Led database design, comprehensive testing, and optimized data retrieval, enhancing overall data efficiency by 33%.
- Customized commercial software for specific business needs following organizational restructuring, tailoring solutions for optimal effectiveness.
- Analyzed business processes, identifying automation opportunities for efficiency enhancements.
- Provided IT-related guidance to both technical and non-technical users, ensuring compliance with security laws and policies.
- Identified anomalies and errors in network and system services, assisted in implementing security measures, and documented security problems in legacy IBM Cognos software.

# Diamond Technologies, Inc. – Wilmington, DE Software Developer (Full time, 40 hours/week)

**April 2021 – November 2022** 

- Provided customer service through client consultation and determined the best problem-solving techniques by analyzing workflow and improving processes.
- Facilitated project management through daily oral communication and secure electronic correspondence with clients.
- Added additional functionality to existing code using .Net, .ASPX, HTML, JavaScript, SQL Relational Databases, WordPress, and Microsoft Access.

# AMANDA M. WILLIAMS, PAGE 2

## NEW CASTLE, DE - 757.828.5756 - AMANDAWILLIAMS1915@GMAIL.COM

- Collaborated with a team of 3 developers to debug code and resolve functionality errors through database administration, increasing uptime by 25%.
- Alleviated unassigned trouble ticket backlog average by 67% and decreased overall open trouble ticket average by 50% by implementing customer-focused problem-solving methods.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

### Zip Code Wilmington - Wilmington, DE

**Software Developer Certification** 

#### **Achievements:**

- Admitted to Zip Code Wilmington's highly competitive software development program which accepts less than 10% of applicants.
- Achieved over 1000 hours of software development experience via projects and training in an immersive training program using Agile and Scrum methodologies and principles.
- Gained experience in full-stack development with a focus on Java, test-driven development, and object-oriented programming.

## Delaware Technical and Community College - Wilmington, DE

Associate of Science Degree – General Science

#### Achievements:

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude (GPA: 4.0)
- President's List (1 Semester)
- Academic Recognition (4 Semesters)